[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas：我认为编程语言是两种截然不同的语言
&gt;&gt; Douglas: I think of programming languages as being in two very distinct
类、系统语言和应用程序语言。
classes, systems languages and application languages.
系统语言是一种用于编写系统内容的语言。
A systems language is a language that you would use for writing system stuff.
需要像内核一样靠近金属的东西，
Something that needs to be close to the metal like a kernel,
设备驱动程序，内存管理器。
a device driver, a memory manager.
那种低级的东西什么都没有。
That kind of low level stuff and nothing else.
其他所有内容都应该用应用程序语言编写。
Everything else should be written in application languages.
现在我们需要一种新的系统语言
Now we need a new system language,
我们占主导地位的系统语言仍然是来自60年代后期的C语言。
our dominant system language is still C which comes from the late 60s.
那是很久以前的事了，我们似乎已经失去了能力
That was a long, long time ago, we seem to have lost the ability
在系统语言中进行创新，并不是说我们不再需要它们了。
to innovate in system languages and it's not like we don't need them anymore.
我认为我们需要一个更好的C版本，但它需要很长的时间。
I think we need a better version of C, but it's a long time coming.
但我更关心的是应用程序语言，
But I'm more concerned with the application languages,
因为那是我们都生活的地方，我们需要更好的应用程序语言。
because that's where we all live and we need better application languages.
我认为一个你可以在很多语言中看到的错误
I think a mistake that you can see in lots of languages
他们对自己站在这条线的哪一边感到困惑。
is that they're confused about which side of this line that they're on.
例如，在我看来，Java最大的设计错误是它不能
For example, for my money the biggest design error in Java was it couldn't
决定它是想成为系统语言还是应用程序语言。
decide if it wanted to be a system language or an application language.
其中一个迹象是它需要使用线程
And one of the signs of that is that it requires the use of threads
在应用程序级别。
at the application level.
我认为这是由于混乱造成的一个悲剧性错误。
Which I think was a tragic mistake due from that confusion.
因此，您可以将应用程序语言划分为两个类。
So you can take the application languages and divide them into two classes.
有古典学派和原型学派。
There's the classical school and the prototypal school.
很长一段时间以来，我一直是原型学校的倡导者
And for a long time I've been an advocate of the prototypal school
因为古典学派存在明显的问题。
because of the obvious problems that are in the classical school.
你已经有了我们讨论过的分类法问题
That you've got the classification taxonomy problem that we talked
关于之前的事。
about earlier.
回到GOTO争论进行的时候，也许是在最响亮的时候，有人发表了
Back when the goto argument was going on, maybe at its loudest, someone published
一篇文章说，我们也应该消除来自的声明。
an article saying we should also eliminate the come-from statement.
这是一个笑话，有人试图设计程序
And it was a joke of it and there were people who attempted to design programming
基于来自语句的语言。
languages based on the come-from statement.
但事实证明我们有来自
But it turns out we have come-from statements in
我们的古典语言，除了我们称之为延伸。
our classical languages except we call it extends.
它所做的事情会导致事物的耦合，耦合可能是一个问题。
And what it does has cause coupling of things and coupling can be a problem.
当你将事物耦合在一起时，一个就会变得依赖于另一个你不能依赖的东西
When you couple things together, then one becomes dependent on the other you cannot
不再独立更改它们。
change them independently anymore.
这导致系统变得脆弱，这在班级系统中发生。
And that causes systems to become brittle and that happens in class systems.
因此原型系统的最大优势就是我们消除了这种耦合。
And so the big advantage in prototypal systems is we eliminate that coupling.
或者我们至少大幅减少它，
Or we at least reduce it significantly,
这样就不再成为问题或进步的障碍。
such that that no longer becomes a problem or a barrier to progress.
所以，作为原型继承的大倡导者。
So, as a big advocate of prototype inheritance.
从那以后我改变了主意
Since then I've changed my mind,
原型最大的好处是节省内存。
that the biggest benefit you get from prototypes is memory conservation.
我认为这可能很重要，可能很重要。
And I think that might have been important, probably was important.
嗯，也许这在1995年并不重要。
Well, maybe it wasn't important in 1995.
现在已经不那么重要了，我们拥有的记忆已经变得如此丰富。
It's not so important now, that we've had memory has become so abundant.
现在，您的口袋中有千兆字节的RAM，并且
You now have gigabytes of RAM in your pocket and
当你无法想象那么多的记忆时。
when you just can't imagine that much memory.
你真的不懂这么大的数字，但我们仍然认为
You really don't understand numbers that big, but we still think about
记忆好像它是以k为单位分发出去的。
memory as though it's doled out in k.
这在当时可能是有道理的，但现在就不那么有道理了。
So may have made sense then, not so much now.
这也是我们拥有财产和继承财产的困惑之源
It also is a source of confusion that we have owned properties and inherited
属性在某些用途上是相同的，但在某些用途上并非如此。
properties which for some purposes act the same, but for some purposes don't.
我在寻找摆脱一切混乱的来源
I'm looking to get rid of all sources of confusion
正如你所知道的，因为混乱会导致错误和利用。
as you know because confusion causes bugs and exploits.
它还提供追溯遗传
It also provides retroactive heredity
您可以在构造对象后更改对象继承的内容。
that you can change what an object inherits after it's constructed.
我还没有发现任何好的用法，但我可以想象很多非常糟糕的用法
I've not found any good uses for this, but I can imagine a lot of really bad uses for
它和它是由这个架构提供的东西。
it and it's something that is provided by this architecture.
它的一个缺点是性能抑制。
One bad thing about it is performance inhibiting.
因此，JavaScript引擎通过对象的形状进行假设来加快速度。
So JavaScript engines go fast by making assumptions about the shape of objects.
当涉及到原型链时，他们必须是悲观的。
And they have to be pessimistic when it comes to prototype chains.
因为原型链可以随时更改其内容
Because a prototype chain can change its contents at any time and
他们需要为此做好准备，这会减慢速度。
they need to be prepared for that and that slows things down.
所以，我过去倾向于原型遗传，
So, I used to be in favor of prototypal inheritance,
我现在支持无类面向对象编程。
I'm now in favor of class free object-oriented programming.
我认为无类面向对象编程是JavaScript的礼物
I think class free object-oriented programming is JavaScript's gift to
人性。
humanity.
我认为这就是为什么这是一种重要的语言。
I think that's why this is an important language.
这就是为什么我希望它成为一种有影响力的语言。
It's why I hope it becomes an influential language.
所以让我们再回顾一遍。
So let's review this again.
这就是块范围。
So this is block scope.
我们有一些函数具有相同的作用域关系和
And we've got functions which have the same scope relationship and
我们又结束了。
we've got our closure again.
我们有这个
And we've got this
非常重要的形式，我们有一个返回函数的函数。
really important form where we have a function that returns a function.
这是我认为历史上最好最重要的发现
And this is I think the best most important discovery in the history
我们有这种愚蠢的小语言。
of programming and we have it in this silly little language.
&gt；&gt；Douglas：最后一次回顾一下，这是我推荐的模型
&gt;&gt; Douglas: So to review one last time, this is the model that I recommend for
进行面向对象的操作
doing object-oriented for
使用JavaScript中的函数进行无类的面向对象编程。
doing class free object-oriented programming using functions in JavaScript.
我们有一个构造函数，它接受一个规范对象。
We've got a constructor which takes a specification object.
我们使我们的实例变量，我们可以
We make our instance variables which we can
从规范对象初始化。
initialize from the specification object.
我们可以获得我们可以使用的其他方法或其他函数
We get other methods or other functions that we can use that we can get
从其他构造函数中调用，我们可以随意调用其中的任意多个。
from other constructors and we can call as many of these as we like.
然后我们创建将关闭所有成员的方法，
We then create our methods which will close over all of the members,
所有其他方法，我们的所有方法和规范对象。
all of the other methods, all of our methods and the specification object.
所有这些都需要公开，
And any of these which need to be public,
我们将放入传出对象，然后将其冻结。
we will put in the outgoing object which we then freeze.
通过这样做，我们得到了一个具有硬接口的对象，
By doing this, we get an object which has a hard interface,
一个不会损坏的接口。
an uncorruptable will interface.
它总是以它应该的方式工作，它不能被混淆。
It will always work exactly the way it should, it cannot be confused.
而且它也纠正了，我认为我们一直存在的一个问题
And it also corrects, I think a problem that we've always had in
对象，因为您希望通过方法访问某些内容。
objects in that some things you want to access through a method.
还有一些只是简单地戳一下属性。
And some simply by poking at the properties.
除非你允许人们去戳他们的房子，
Except if you allow people to poke at the properties,
那么就没有针对不一致的防御。
then there is no defense against inconsistency.
所有的一切，至少对象的所有更改都应该通过接口。
Everything, all changes at least to the object should go through the interfaces.